<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"  [ ]>
<chapter id="social.fiveminutes">
  <title>Seam Social in 5 minutes</title>
  
  <para>
    The Web example app is quite simple and gives a good idea of the possibilities with Seam Social.
    The main steps you need to take to use Seam Social are:
  </para>
  
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>Declare an OAuth configuration</listitem>
    <listitem>Inject an <code>OAuthService</code> bean</listitem>
    <listitem>Request the Authorization URL for the service and get a request token</listitem>
    <listitem>Store the verifier in the <code>OAuthService</code> bean and initialize the access token</listitem>
    <listitem>Use the service</listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  
  <para>
    Should you need to fully understand each step, the complete OAuth lifecycle can be found 
    <ulink url="https://dev.twitter.com/docs/auth/oauth">here</ulink> or 
    <ulink url="https://developer.linkedin.com/documents/authentication">here</ulink>.
  </para>
  
  <section>
    <title>Declaring an OAuth Configuration</title>
    
    <para>
      To consume an OAuth service you need to declare an application on the service platform (i.e. for
      Twitter you can do this at <ulink url="https://dev.twitter.com/apps/new"/>.  The declaration of an
      application is done with the <code>@OAuthApplication</code> annotation which must contain at least:
    </para>
    
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>An OAuth API public key</listitem>
      <listitem>An OAuth API private/secret key</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>
      If you don't know what this is about, please refer to the OAuth concepts in your service documentation.
    </para>
    
    <para>
      To use an OAuth Service Bean in Seam Social you need to provide the following configuration information
      by producing the right <code>OAuthService</code> bean:
    </para>
    
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Via a producer method or subclassing</listitem>
      <listitem>Via an XML configuration (Using Solder's bean configuration feature).</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  
  <section>  
    <title>Configuration with a producer method or a bean definition</title>
    
    <para>
      The simplest way to configure your service is to create a producer method like so:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[   @OAuthApplication(apiKey = "FQzlQC49UhvbMZoxUIvHTQ", apiSecret = "VQ5CZHG4qUoAkUUmckPn4iN4yyjBKcORTW0wnok4r1k")
    @Twitter
    @Produces
    TwitterService twitterServiceProducer(TwitterService ts) {
        return ts;
    }]]></programlisting>
    
    <para>
      You can also create a bean by subclassing the implementation of the service like this:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[  @OAuthApplication(apiKey = "FQzlQC49UhvbMZoxUIvHTQ", apiSecret = "VQ5CZHG4qUoAkUUmckPn4iN4yyjBKcORTW0wnok4r1k")
    @Twitter
    public class MyTwitterBean extends TwitterServiceJackson {
    
…
}]]></programlisting>

    <para>
      The API key and API secret are provided by the service you want to consume (here Twitter).
      You can use the values above since they're coming from the "Seam Social" Twitter application.
      The callback depends on your application - it's the URL that will collect the OAuth verifier.
    </para>
      
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Injecting the Service Bean into your code</title>
    
    <para>
      You can now inject the bean with the right service qualifier:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[@Named
@SessionScoped
public class mySessionBean implements Serializable {
    ...
    @Inject
    @Twitter
    TwitterService service;
    ...
}]]></programlisting>

  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Request the OAuth authorization URL</title>
    
    <para>
      You can now ask for the authorization URL for your service:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[String authURL = service.getAuthorizationUrl();]]></programlisting>
    
    <para>
      Calling this URL will bring the user on the service connection page and right delegation for the
      application.  If the user gives rights to the application to use the service on their behalf the 
      service will send you back a special code (verifier) that you must inject into the service to 
      initiate the connection.      
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Set the verifier and initiate connection</title>
    
    <para>
      As the verifier comes back to the application after an action of the final user, you have to set up
      a servlet or a JSF page (the URL of which is the callback URL you configured when you set up the 
      service) to catch it and add it to the current session.  Here is an example with JSF:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[<f:metadata>
    <f:viewParam name="#{mySessionBean.twitterService.verifierParamName}"
        value="#{mySessionBean.twitterService.verifier}"
                 required="true"
                 requiredMessage="Error with Twitter. Retry later"/>
    <f:event type="preRenderView"
        listener="#{mySessionBean.twitterService.initAccessToken()}"/>
</f:metadata>]]></programlisting>

    <para>
      The service is now connected - you have an access token.
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section>
    <title>Send request to the service</title>
    
    <para>
      You can now use the service with your rights:
    </para>
    
    <programlisting><![CDATA[TwitterProfile user = twitter.getMyProfile();
String fullName = user.getFullName();]]></programlisting>
  </section>

</chapter>
